Surprise!
奖喜 !
Alex. Do not interrupt me when I'm daydreaming.
型力，别打援我发白日葛
When a zebra's in the zone, leave him alone.
班台发葛时别理煌
Come on, Marty. Just wanted to wish you a happy birthday.
马提，祝你生日快乐
Hey, man, thanks.
多谢呼
Hey, I got something stuck in my teeth.
我牙彰塞著些东西
It's driving me crazy. Can you help me? Please?
潭身不自在，才我看看
You came to the right place, my friend.
找对人了
Dr. Marty, D.D.S., is in the house.
我是牙医马提
Please hop on top of my sterilized examination table, if you may.
请跳上检查要树
- [don't see anything. - It's on the left.
什么也看不见 左下
Oh, sorry.
对不起
Okay, just don't talk with your mouth full.
嘴里有食物别说话
Right here. What the heck is this doing in there?
找到了，怎会找到这东西 ?
Happy birthday!
生日快乐 !
Aw, hey, thanks, man.
嘿，多谢呀
You put it in behind the tooth. You all right.
竞藏在牙郑后面，属害
These aren't even on the shelf yet. Here. Check it out.
还未有得走，看真一点
- Look at that. Ooh! Look at that. - Look at that. It's snowing.
化静，效靓 ! 还会下雪
Ten years old, huh? A decade.
十功了吧 ?
Double digits. The big 1-0.
驳位数了，1 - 0
You don't like it?
不喜欢 ?
- No, no, it's great. - You hate it.
不，很好 讨原它
I should've gotten you the Alex alarm clock. That's the big seller.
该送你热问的亚力病鳃
No, no, no. The present's great, really.
不，这礼物很好，真的
It's just that another year's come and gone
只是年复年
and I'm still doing the same old thing.
我还是老样子
"Stand over here. Trot over there. Eat some grass. Walk back over here."
站在这壬，跳去那站，吃吃草
- l see your problem. - Maybe I should go to law school.
我明白 或该去读法律
You just need to break out of that boring routine.
你只需打破常规
- How? - Throw out the old act.
怎样打破 ? 抛秦指定动作
Who knows what you'll do. Make it up as you go along.
列村守成规
Ad lib. Improvise. On the fly. Boom, boom, boom.
号出框框，随心所谷
- Really? - You know, make it fresh.
真的? 最紧要好玩
Fresh, huh? Okay. I could do fresh.
好玩 ? 我可以好玩
Works for me.
我可以
Here come the people, Marty. I love the people.
人来哆，我党他们
It's fun people fun time!
一来就好玩
Let's go, Gloria! Up and at'em. We're open!
歌莉垩，起身，开工啦 !
What day is it?
星期疲?
It's Friday. Field trip day.
星期五，是参观日
Yes, it's field trip day. Let's get up and go...
参观日，快起身了…
..in ten more minutes.
让我多睡十分甸
Melman, Melman, Melman!
递文，六文，遵文1 1 1!
Wake up! Rise and shine! It's another fabulous morning in the Big Apple.
起身 ! 纽约市朝气牵牵的一天
Let's go.
走吧
- Not for me. I'm calling in sick. - What?
我今天请病假 什么 ?
I found another brown spot on my shoulder. Right here. See?
我说膀多了一点，看
Right there. You see?
就在这里，看
Melman, you know it's all in your head. Hm?
遵文，是你心理作用
Let's go! Come on!
…大家快点 !
Phil! Wake up, you filthy monkey.
阿菲，起身啦，训龊马胸
Oh, I'm going to be fresh.
我一定要好玩
Straight out the ground. Tasty fresh! Freshalicious.
由地下开始，一定好玩
Ziploc fresh.
用了密实袋般新鲜
Ladies and gentlemen, children of all ages,
各位先生女士，小朋友们
the Central Park Zoo proudly presents:
中央公园动物园诚意献上 :
Show them the cat. Who's the cat?
台柱，谁是台柱 ?
The king of New York City.
经约市之王
Alex the lion.
狮子王亚力
It's showtime.
表演了时间
Gather around, people. Big show about to start.
猜彩表演即将开始
Check out the zebra taking care of biz. That's right.
看斑马大展身手
Just smile and wave, boys.
大家微笑挥手
Smile and wave.
微笑挥手
Kowalski, progress report.
高华斯基，进度报告
We're 500 feet from the main sewer line.
距疮主渠还羡500只
- And the bad news? - We've broken our last shovel.
壤消息呢? 最后个镀也断了
Rico, you're on litter patrol. We need shovels.
力高，再搜这圾堆，找个新镀
And find more Popsicle sticks. We don't want to risk another cave-in.
还要雪休棍，不可再南下求
And me, skipper?
队长，我呢?
I want you to look cute and cuddly, private.
多续扮可党
Today we're going to blow this dump.
今天我们就离开这守
Come here. Come here. Come on, penguin.
过来，明来，企镶明来
Yeah! You don't see that on Animal Planet.
动物星球频道看不到的
Well, show's over, folks. Thanks for coming.
表演完旱，多认光枚
l hope you thought it was fresh.
希望大家认为有创意啦
I'l be here all week.
我一星期都在这壬
In fact, I'll be here for my whole life.
我一生都会在这壬
Three hundred and sixty-five days a year,
一年365日…
including Christmas, Hanukkah, Halloween, Kwanzaa.
包括可诈节、光明节、菌村和节
Please don't forget to never spay or neuter your pets.
别总了替才物绝育
And tip your cabbie, because he's broke.
给的士司机贴士，他很宕
You, quadruped. Sprechen sie Englisch?
四脚动物，会说英语吧 ?
I sprechen.
我会
- What continent is this? - Manhattan.
这是什么大陆 ? 曼哈上顿
Hoover Dam! We're still in New York.
惨 ! 我们还在纽约
Abort. Dive! Dive! Dive.
取消行动 尖!淤!海!
Hey. You in the tux. Wait a minute.
嘿，等一障
What are you guys doing?
你们在做什么 ?
We're digging to Antarctica.
我们掘秘道去南极济
Ant-who-tica?
南什么济 ?
Can you keep a secret, my monochromatic friend?
单色朋友，可宇秘密 ?
Do you ever see any penguins running free around New York City?
可见过企炉在弓约市奔走?
Of course not. We don't belong here. It's just not natural.
当然没见过，我们不属於这壬
This is all some kind of whacked-out conspiracy.
这当中一定有险谋
We're going to the wide-open spaces of Antarctica.
我们要去广阅的南极洲
To the wild.
去野外
The wild? You could actually go there?
野外? 真的可以去?
That sounds great.
太好了
Hey, hold up. Where is this place? Tell me where it is.
这地方在哪里?告诉我
You didn't see anything.
你什么也没看网
Right?
是哮?
Yes, sir.
看见
I'm sorry. No, sir.
对不起，没看网
For his final appearance of the day,
弓约市之王…
the king of New York City.
…今日最后亮相
Alex the lion.
狮子王亚力
Thank you. Thank you very much.
多讲，多谢大家
You guys are great. You're a great crowd. Give yourselves a hand.
你们太好了，请为自己鼓掌
Thank you. Oh. Thank you.
多澳 噢，多潮
Oh! Well. Thank you.
好，多误
Oh, that's too kind. Too kind.
太客气，太客气
Underpants!
底裤 !
Everybody get home safe. Hey! Check out my Web site.
安全回家，记住潮览我的网页
Twenty-four hour Alex Cam. Watch me sleep.
24小时直播，看我睡觉
This is the life.
这才叫享受
That's the spot.
就是那点
Ohl! I'm in heaven.
我升亿了
- Ooh, it's Marty's birthday. - Just rip it open.
噢，今天是马提的生日 扯有开它
- What is it? - Come on. Open it up. What you got?
是什么 ? 拆并看看是什么
A thermometer.
温度计
Thanks. I love it, Melman. I love it.
递文，讲谢，我很喜欢
l wanted to give you something personal. That was my first rectal thermometer.
想送些特别东西给你 我第一支昵股探热针
- Mother... - I'll miss that bad boy.
他杂… 我很不拾得
Get the cake. Melman, come on.
拿蛋糕来，遵文，快来唱歌
Happy birthday to you
祝你生日快乐
You live in a zoo
你你动物园住
You look like a monkey
成副马允样
And you smell like one too
仲有股歼味
I say.
我不同意
Aw, well, now, you guys are just embarrassing me.
你们令我很灼座
And yourselves.
选有你们自己
What? We worked on that all week.
我们排练了一整星期
Let's go. Let's make a wish, babycakes.
许个磊
- What'd you wish for? - Nope. Can't tell you that.
许了什么灰 ? 不能告诉你
Come on. Tell.
讲啦
No siree. I'm telling you, it's bad luck.
不行，会行训运的
You want some bad luck, I'll blab it out.
你想行训运，我便告诉你
But if you want to be safe, I'll keep my mouth shut.
否则我要守口如瓶
Would you just tell us? What could happen?
讲啦，会发生什么事 ?
l wished I could go to the wild!
我希望可以去野外 !
The wild?!
野外?
I told you it was bad luck.
我讲明会行衰运的
The wild? Are you nuts?
野外?你俐了?
That is the worst idea I've ever heard.
那是我取过最差的顾望
It's unsanitary.
那儿不卫生
The penguins are going. So why can't I?
企炉也走了，我们为何不去 ?
The penguins are psychotic.
企鸣有精神病
Come on. Just imagine going back to nature.
试想想回包大自然的怀抱
Back to your roots. Clean air, wide-open spaces!
返回自己的根 清新空气，广半空间
I hear there's wide-open spaces in Connecticut.
册说康万狄克州也很大
- Connecticut? - You got to go over to Grand Central.
康万狄克州 ? 你先要去中央火车站…
Then you got to take the Metro-North train... north?
然后乘火车向北…北?
So one could take the train? Just hypothetically.
火车可以去到 ? 假设去的话
Come on. What would Connecticut have to offer us?
康万狄克州可以给我们什么 ?
- Lyme disease. - Thank you, Melman.
关节炎 谢谢，苯文
No, I just want...
不，我只是想…
There's none of this in the wild.
野外绝扰这个
This is a highly refined type of food thing
野外经扼这等…
that you do not find in the wild.
高级处理食物
You ever thought there might be more to life than steak, Alex?
亚力，人生比牛扒重要
He didn't mean that, baby. No, no, no.
裤贝，他没恶意的
Doesn't it bother you guys that you don't know anything
你们对外面的世界一盘所知…
about life outside this zoo?
不党朵愧吗 ?
Well, ! mean, come on. That's just one subject.
不过是一个话题蜂了
You got a little schmutz right there on your....
你脸上有食物渣洲…
Thanks, guys. Thanks for the party. It was great.
讲谢你们的派对，好极了
Really.
真的
What's eating him?
他怎广了?
Maybe you should talk to him. Go over and give him a little pep talk.
或许你去和他好好谈谈
Hey, I already gave him a snow globe. I can't top that.
我已送了礼，扰能为力
l can see where this is going.
又要状个没完没了
It is getting late. I guess I'm going to...
已夜深，我要…
Come on. He's your best friend.
他是你的好朋友
All right, all right. Okay.
好吧，好吧
- Night, Marty. - Night, Glo.
马提，晚安 歌痢亚，晚安
What a day.
又一天
I mean, I tell you, it just doesn't get any better than this, you know?
生活不会比现时更好的了
Ooh! It just did. Even the star's out.
噢，锦上添花，星也出来了
Not going to find a star like that in the wild.
野外找不到这星
Helicopter.
直界机
Marty. Buddy. Listen.
老友，黄住
Everybody has days when they think the grass might be greener somewhere else.
每人都想到外面看看
Alex.
亚力
Look at me.
你看我
I'm ten years old. My life is half over.
我已十功，人生遇了一半
And I don't even know if I'm black with white stripes...
连自己究竟黑底和白班…
...or white with black stripes.
抑或白底黑斑都不知
I'm thinking of a song.
我想起一首歌
Alex. Please. Not now.
亚力，我没心情
Oh, yes. It's a wonderful song. I think you're familiar with it.
动节的歌，你一定会唱
Oh, no. Oh, no, you don't. No, no, no.
不，不，不要唱
I'm not listening.
我不了
Start spreadin' the news
开始散人饰消息…
I don't know you.
我不认识你
I'm leaving today
我今天要离开
- We are a great big part of it - He's funny. Who is that?
我们一起去 他是谁?
Come on. You know you know the words.
你记得歌词
Two little words.
十个字
New York.
经约
Shut up, shut up, shut up! Hey, I'm sleeping here!
收声，我在睡党 !
We're not all nocturnal, you know!
我们不是夜间动物 !
I'll Knock your "turnal" right off, pal.
我打到你是
Yeah, you and what army, stripes?
你班兄弟呢，斑珊伐?
You mess with him, you mess with me, Howard.
同他遇不去，即同我过不去
- You're a bigmouth lion. - See? Mr. Grumpy Stripes.
真大口气 看见唉，斑马伐 ?
We make a great team, the two of us.
我们是欧幻组合
We sure do. No doubt about it.
绝对是，反庸置疑
So, what are you going to do? Go running off to the wild by yourself?
打算怎样 ? 独自去野外 ?
- No. - Good.
不会 好的
You and me. Let's go.
你和我一起去
- What? - The wild.
什么 ? 去野外
Come on. You and me together.
你和我雨个
It's a straight shot down Fifth Avenue to Grand Central.
宙第五街直落便是中央火车站
Weill grab a train, we'll head north.
乘火车向北行
We can be back by morning. No one will ever know.
早上回来，没人会发现
You're joking. Right?
你在说笑吧?
Yeah. I'm joking. Of course I'm joking. Give me a break.
当然，我当然在说笑
Like we're going to get a train.
我债怎会去乘火车
Don't do that. You really had me worried there.
别说这种笑话，我会担心
Oh, well. 1 guess I'll hit the sack.
好吧，我要睡了
Yeah, me too. I'll need to rest my voice for tomorrow.
我也是，要省些力气
It's Seniors' Day, you know. Have to roar extra loud.
明天是长者日，要叫大声哑
Give them a little jolt. You know?
给他们多些动
Good night, AllyAl.
晚安
They forgot to turn off the ambience again.
又总记关罚人造气氛装置
Don't worry. It's cool.
么问题
You know, I got it.
我来处理
Much better.
好多了
Come on, now, baby.
裤贞，来啦
My little filet.
我的小牛扒
My little filet mignon with a little fat around the edges.
有人少少肥这的失扒
like that. I like a little fat on my steak.
我训欢有一点肥音
My sweet, juicy steak. You are a rare delicacy.
美味的牛扒
Alex. Alex. Alex!
亚力 1 亚力1垩力!
What? What?
什么 ? 什么 ?
You suck your thumb?
你受拇指?
What is it, Melman?
六文，什么事 ?
You know how I have that bladder infection
我膀胱炎
and I have to get up every two hours?
每雨小时要去方便
I got up to pee and looked over at Marty's pen, which I usually don't do.
我去看马担，平时不会的
I don't know why, but I did. And...
不知何故我今次会…
What? What's going on?
究竟怎广了 ?
It's Marty. He's gone.
马提走了
Gone! What do you mean, "gone"?
走了?什么意思 ?
How long has he been working on this?
他控了多久 ?
Marty!
马提 !
He wouldn't fit down there.
他穿不明去的
Marty? Marty! Marty!
马提?马提1!马提!
This doesn't make any sense. Where would he go?
莫名其妙，他去了哪里 ?
- Connecticut! - He wouldn't.
康乃狄克剂 ! 不会
Oh, no! What are we going to do?
我们该怎广办 ?
I mean, we got to call somebody!
要叫人来蓝忙 !
Hello? Get me Missing Animals. And hurry.
咀，搭线去失中动物组
We've got a lost zebra probably on the way to Connecticut, and we need...
有斑马失跑 去康乃狄克剂途中…
- Hello? Hello? - Wait a second.
咀?喂? 等一委
- We can't call the people. - What the...?
不能通知人类 搞什么… ?
They'll be really mad.
他们会发火
It'll get Marty transferred for good. Don't bite the hand that feeds you.
会把马提放逐，弄巧成抽
Mm-hm, I know that's right.
说得对
We got to go after him. He's not thinking straight.
去追他，他错牛角拓
Let's stop him from making the biggest mistake of his life.
阻正他犯下经天大罪
He's probably out there lost and cold, confused.
他或饥寒交迫、六神拖主
Poor little guy.
小可情
Come on.
一起去
One of us should wait here in case he comes back.
其中一人要留下，万一他回来
Not now. This is an intervention. We all got to go.
这炊要总动员，一起去
What's the fastest way to Grand Central?
最快途径去中央火车站 ?
- You should take Lexington. - Melman!
你该由列斯顿方向去 邀文 !
- Okay. "We." We should take Lexington. - What about Park?
“我们”应该由列斯顿去 柏靓大道呢?
No, Park goes two ways. You can't time the lights.
驳线行车，很花时间
l heard Tom Wolfe is speaking at Lincoln Center.
聘说有人在林肯中心演讲
Well, of course we're going to throw poo at him.
一定要去送臭臭给他
We should've taken Park.
早知行柏宇大道
You sure this is the fastest way to Grand Central Station?
这是最快途径 ?
I don't know! That's what Melman said.
我不清楚，遵文说是的
Hey. Hey, you, guys.
咀，喂!
That room has some nifty little sinks you can wash up in, and look!
洗手间有个型盘可以洗面
Free mints!
免费薄荷糖 !
This isn't a field trip.
这不是参观日
This is an urgent mission to save Marty from throwing his life away.
是摊救马提毁减的紧急行动
Now, where's the train?
火车呢 ?
Here it comes.
来了
What did Marty say to you? l asked you to talk to him.
马提说了什么 ? 我叫你跟他谈
I did! I did! 1 don't understand. He said, "Let's go."
我有 ! 他说“一起走^
I said, "Are you crazy?" He says, "I'm ten years old."
我说“你疯了?“ 他说“我十功了“
And he has black-and-white stripes, and so then we sang and...
说有黑白敏，然后我们唱歌…
What you got to do is go straight back down West 42nd.
掉头向西面42街走
It's on your left after Vanderbilt.
过了云德比街后在你左方
If you hit the Chrysler Building, you've gone too far.
见到佳士拿大广，那太记了
Thanks a lot, officer.
谢谢警察先生
Hey! Wait for the light.
等绿灯 !
Freak.
怪人
- Did you say "zebra"? - That's right. A zebra.
斑马? 是，一焦斑马
Right in front of me.
就在我前面
- Can I shoot it? - Negative.
可以开检吐? 不行
Then I'm going to need some backup.
要人支援
- Aw! Knicks lost again. - What are you going to do.
唉，纽约队又输了 那又如何
Did that say "Grand Central Station" or "my aunt's constipation"?
它说“中央火车站“ 或“姨杂便秘场”?
Grand Central Station.
中央火车站
It's grand and it's central.
果然又中又天
Move aside. We have an emergency here. This is an emergency situation.
大家让并，有紧急事故
Hey, hey. Just chill out. It's not that big of an emergency.
冷静，也不是那广紧急
Upstairs, downstairs.
上五时，下五叶
How do you like that?
知敬未?
Lady! What is wrong with you?
阿婆 ! 你怎太了?
Ow! Get a grip on yourselves, people.
大家冷静
You're a bad kitty.
壕和猫咪
Dagnabbit! 1 missed the express.
倒霉 ! 错过了快车
Looks like I'll have to take the Stamford local.
看来要乘普通车了
I got him! I've got him!
找到他 ! 找到他 !
He's got him!
他找到他 !
He's got him! He's got...
他找到他 ! 他找到他 !
got something for you!
有东西给你
I'm okay. I'm okay.
我没事，我疫事
Whoa! What are you guys doing here?
你们来这和里干什么 ?
- lam so glad we found you. - We were so worried about you.
真高萎找到你 ! 很担心
Don't worry, I'm fine, I'm fine. Look at me. I'm fine.
列担心，我没事，没事
You're fine? Oh, he's fine. Oh, great.
你没事? 他没事，好极
You hear that? Marty's fine. That's good to know.
匠见哮? 马提没事，太好了
Because I was wondering...
因为我在想…
How could you do this to us? I thought we were your friends!
你怎可这样对我们 ? 我们是朋友 !
What's the big deal? l was coming back.
有什么大不了?我会回去的
Don't ever do this again. Do you hear me?
列再出走，孤见叶?
- Do you hear him? - Guys, we're running out of time.
你贩见叶? 我们没时间了
Oh, Melman, you broke their clock?
遵文，你打烟了他们的钾?
...do this again! Don't you ever, ever do this again!
…列再出走 ! 列再这柑做 !
Come here.
过来
We've been ratted out, boys.
被出南了
Hold your fire!
不要开检 !
Cute and cuddly, boys. Cute and cuddly.
扮可爱、得意，可爱、得意
If you have any poo, fling it now.
有臭臭，现在括啦
It's the Man.
是人类
Good evening, officers.
警察晚安
No. No. No. You don't talk now. Okay?
不，不，不，你别说话
You're not good with the “putting words together
你狗嘴吐不出象牙
and their coming out good" thing. You keep it "shh."
只管并上踢巴
Hey! How you doing? You know what? Everything's cool.
大家好，一切安好
We just had a little situation here. Little internal situation.
我们之间有些小问题
My friend went a little crazy. Happens to everybody.
我朋友一时锐牛角尖
The city gets to us all. Went a little cuckoo in the head.
生活在都市 会令人有吕神经贸
Don't be calling me cuckoo in the head.
列说我神经贸
Just shush! I will handle this.
唆 ! 由我来
Ohl! I got him!
搞定
Go, go, go! Right here, please.
走，走!留在这壬
Would you give a guy a break?
大家划个忙
Weill take my little friend home and forget this ever happened. All right?
我们带这朋友回家 忘记今晚的事
No harm, no foul, right?
当扼事发生通
Hey, it's cool. It's me, Alex the lion. From the zoo.
是我，狂子王亚力
What's the matter with them?
他们究竟怎庆了 ?
l feel really, really weird.
我感觉很奇县
I love you guys.
我爱大家
I love you so much.
我非常爱你们
Last night's dramatic incident in Grand Central
昨晚在中央火车站发生的事…
is an example of what animal rights wackos have been shouting for years:
动物权力热心份子 多年来的诉求
Animals clearly don't belong in captivity.
动物不该被囚禁
They are to be sent back to their natural habitat,
现把物们送返大自然…
where they will live their lives in the freedom they desire.
重享渴望的自由
- Hey. Little help? - He's awake! He's awake!
扶起我吐? 醒了!醒了!
Do something!
搞定他 !
Oh, my head.
我头痛
What the...?
发生… ?
Wait. Where? What?
等等，哪里?什么 ?
I'm in a box! Oh, no. No, no! Not the box.
我在箱内 ! 不，不能在箱内 !
Oh, no, they can't transfer me. Not me!
不可以送走我，不可以!
Oh, I can't breathe. I can't breathe.
透不过气，透不过气
Darkness creeping in.
黑暗把我包围
Walls closing in around me.
世界把我阳绝
So alone. So alone.
孤独被遗素
- Alex! Alex, are you there? - Marty?
亚力1是你吗? 马提 !
- Yeah! Talk to me, buddy. - Oh, Marty! You're here!
是，就话呀! 马提 ! 你也在
- What's going on? You okay? - This doesn't look good.
发生什么事 ? 你没事吧 ? 情况不妙
- Alex, Marty, is that you? - Gloria!
亚力、台提? 歌痢亚 !
- You're here too! - lam loving the sound of your voice.
你也在 ! 台见你声音太好了
- What is going on? - We're all in crates.
发生什么事 ? 我们全被困在箱 内
- Sleeping just knocks me out. - Melman!
邀文 !
Is that Melman?
是前文吗 ?
- Are you okay? - Yeah. No, I'm fine.
你没事吧 ? 我没事
l often doze off while I'm getting an MRI.
照完磁力共震都会睡著
- You're not getting an MRI. - CAT scan?
这不是磁力共震 电脑抬描?
No CAT scan. It's a transfer. It's a zoo transfer.
不是 我们被转送去另一动物园
Zoo transfer?! Oh, no. No, no, I can't be transferred.
被恩送 ? 不行，不能被夸送
l have an appointment with Dr. Goldberg at 5:00.
我五点约了医生
There are prescriptions that have to be filled.
我一定要服药
No other zoo could afford my medical care.
没其他动物园肯支付医药痪
And 1am not going HMO.
我不要社署的医疗保健
Take it easy, Melman. It's going to be okay.
遵文，别紧张
- We are going to be okizay. - No, we're not going to be okizay.
没事的 不，我们不会没事的
Now, because of you, we're ruined!
全因为你，我们前途喜毁
Because of me? fail to see how this is my fault.
因为我?和为何是我的错
- You're kidding, right, Marty? - You. You ticked off the people.
你不知原因 ? 你，是你激怒了人类
You bit the hand, Marty. You bit the hand.
你食碗面反碗底
"l don't know who I am. I got to go find myself in the wild." Oh, please.
要去野外找回自我“
I did not ask you to come after me, did I?
我没叫你跟著我来
He does have a point.
他也有道理
I did say we should stay at the zoo, but you guys...
我叫大家在动物园等他…
Melman, just shut it.
六文，收纪
You suggested this idea to him in the first place.
是你教他乘火车的
- Leave Melman out of this. - Thank you, Gloria.
别蛮涉遵文 谢谢歌莉亚
Besides, it's not my fault that we were transferred.
亚力，不是我丸大家被送走
Melman, shut it. Does anybody feel nauseous?
六文，收纪 可有人感到作哎?
- l feel nauseous. - Melman, you always feel nauseous.
我感到作哎 递文，你经常感到作哎
Progress report.
进度报告
It's an older code, skipper. I can't make it out.
队长，蔷式密码，解不来
You, higher mammal.
你，高等哺乳动物
Can you read?
可识字 ?
No. Phil can read, though. Phil.
不，阿菲会 阿菲
Ship to Kenya.
去肯亚
Wildlife preserve.
野生动物保护区
Africa!
非浏!
Africa? That ain't going to fly. Rico.
非浏?力高，不对路
I was the star in the greatest city on Earth.
我是地球上出色的名星
- Guys, listen. - Aking. Loved by my people.
大家取住 受菌人爱戴
- Let's be civil. - And you've ruined everything!
理智点 一切都被你毁溅
"Loved"?
爱戴 ?
If the people loved you, it's only because they didn't know the real you!
人类过你因为未见你的真面目
Don't make me come up there. I'll whoop both of yall.
别逼我上来教训你俩
I thought I knew the real you!
我以为我认识你 !
Your black-and-white stripes, they cancel each other out. You're nothing!
马提，你的黑白斑丝 害你一德所有 !
Stop it, stop it, stop it!
停止 ! 停止 ! 停止 !
Status.
最新情况
It's no good. I don't know the codes.
情况不妙，解码不成功
Don't give me excuses. Give me results! Navigation.
别诸多藉口，我要结果 !
All right. Let me think.
好吧，等我想想
And shut him up!
叫他收志 !
- I did it! - Let's get this tin can turned around.
我成功 ! 把船掉头
Guys?
有人吗?
Gloria!
歌痢亚 !
Melman!
邀文 !
Marty!
马提 !
Alex!
亚力!
Marty?!
马提? !
Marty!
马提 !
No, wait. Come back, Marty!
等等，马提，回来 !
Don't go.
不要走
Marty?
马提?
Melman?
遵文 ?
Gloria?
歌莉亚?
Marty?!
马提? !
Melman?!
遵文? !
Gloria?!
歌痢开? !
Marty!
马提 !
Melman! Gloria!
邀文 ! 歌痢亚 !
Hey, anyone! Hello!
任何人 ! 咀?
Marty, Melman, Gloria.
马提、遵文、歌莉亚
Gloria, Melman, Marty. Marty, Gelman, Gloria. Marty, Melman.
歌痢亚、遵文
Morty, Morty, Gelman. Regis. Kelly.
马提、歌文
Matt, Katie, Al.
歌莉亚
Get me out of this thing. Somebody. Hello?
有人吗? 救我出去，有人吗?
Get me out of this thing right now!
马上救我出去 !
Hello? Somebody?
咀?有人吧?
Melman!
邀文 !
Alex? Is that you?
亚力1是你吗?
Melman, I got you. Hang on! Hang on. I got you.
散文，我来救你，站稳
Melman! I got you, buddy.
遭文，我帮你
Wait a sec, Melman. Wait right there.
遵文，等等，就在那守
- What are you doing? - I'm getting you out of the box.
你做什么 ?
- Relax. - Alex?
放基 亚力?
Giraffe, corner pocket!
长鹿球，入尾袋
Here goes nothing!
兵行险将
- Wait, wait, wait, wait. - Hold still!
放基
- Wait, Alex. - Hold still.
型力，等等
- No, come on. - Here I come!
不，等等 我来啦 !
Look! Look! Look! Look!
看1看!看!看!
It's Gloria. It's Gloria!
是歌痢亚 ! 歌莉亚 !
Oh, hey, it is Gloria.
是歌痢邢 !
Gloria!
歌痢亚 !
Alrighty, boys, fun's over.
好哎，玩金了
Alex!
亚力!
- Marty?! - Marty!
马提? ! 马提 !
Left! Left! Left. No, no, your left! Your left! Your left!
左!堪1!不，你的左方 !
Right here's good.
这壬可以了
I don't have anything on me right now. I'll have to get you later.
我身上没线，膛些付给你们
To you too.
你也保重
Marty!
马提 !
Alex!
亚力!
Alex?
亚力?
Oh, sugar, honey, ice tea.
噢，西瓜、竟果、香车、栖
- Hold up! - I'm going to kill you!
等等 我要角掉你 !
- Come here! Don't run away from me! - Calm down!
遇来，别逃 ! 冷静 !
If you keep running, I'm going to just kill you more!
再逃的详，我更加火渡
Oh, look at us.
看我们
We're all here together. Safe and sound.
安然乱羡地一起在这壬
Yeah, here we are.
是，一起在这壬
Where exactly is "here"?
这和里究竟是什么地方 ?
San Diego.
圣地牙哥
San Diego?
台地牙哥?
White sandy beaches,
白沙海滩…
cleverly simulated natural environment, wide-open enclosures.
…仿天然环境，广阅空间
I'm telling you, this could be the San Diego Zoo.
这和里可能是忆地牙可动物转
Complete with fake rocks.
甚至有人造石头
Wow, that looks real.
哇，真的一样
San Diego? What could be worse than San Diego?
会有什么比忆地牙哥还盖 ?
I don't know. This place is crackalacking!
不清楚，但这地方一流呀 !
Oh, I could hang here. l could hang here.
我可以住下来
- I'll kill you! - Take it easy!
我般掉你 ! 别紧张 !
- Strangle you! - Calm down.
撑死你 !
Then bury you, dig you up, clone you and kill your clones.
然后埋了你、气出来复沁 愉清你的复自版
- 20-second timeout. - I'll never talk to you again.
从此不再晓你
Now, look. We're just going to find the people,
匠住，我们去找人问问…
get checked in and have this mess straightened out.
把一切事情再清楚
Oh, great. This is just great. San Diego.
好极，太好了，忆地牙哥
Now I'll have to compete with Shamu and his smug little grin.
要和和荷里活杀人入各宁
I can't top that. Can't top it.
我做不来，会比下去
I'm ruined! I'm done. I'm out of the business.
没有希望，前途总负
It's your fault, Marty! You've ruined me.
马提，是你的错! 你毁了我 !
Come on, Alex. Do you honestly think
亚力，你以入…
l intended all of this to happen?
我著意的吗?
You want me to say that I'm sorry? Is that what you want?
你想我道歉，是鄙?
Okay, I'm...
好 9 我…
He just shushed me.
他叫我收纪
Marty, look, you've got to be just a little bit more und...
马提，你要明白…
- Don't you shush me. - Do you hear that? Don't you hear that?
不要趴我 匠见哮?你们可孤见 ?
- hear it now. - Where there's music, there's people.
现在册见 有音乐的地方就有人
- Go to the head honcho. - A sidewalk would be nice.
去找话事人 不如走平路
Yeah, what a dump.
这地方真差动
They should call it the San Di-lame-o Zoo.
该叫、加州暮仔园“
First they tell you, "We got this great open plan thing. Let animals run wild."
先告诉我们一望扰际的设计 让动物自由奔放跑跳
Next thing, flowers in your hair, everybody's hugging everybody.
炙而用花环来坎迎我们
This place kind of grows on you. This way, guys! Come on!
这和里念来念讨好，跟我来 !
What the...?
他杂…
Okay, let's make a good impression on the people.
留个好印象给人
Smiles, everyone. Let's get it together.
大家笑，别失礼
- ls that the best you can do? - Oh, I'm not smiling. It's gas.
你只能这样吗 ? 我不是笑，是胃气
Well, great. Let's make gas look good.
好吧，俊管笑吧
- Wow! - It's not people. It's animals.
不是人类，是动物
California animals. Dude.
老友，是加州夸皮士
This is like a Puffy party.
像是狂野派对
What kind of zoo is this?
这是什么动物园 ?
I just saw 26 blatant health code violations.
已约现26处违反本生休例
I'm loving San Diego. This place is off the chizain.
我党忌地牙哥，至好玩
Twenty-seven.
27处
We should've brought chips and dip.
应该带手信求
Wait.
等等
Where's Alex? What happened to him? He was right behind us. Wasn't he?
亚力?他不是在我们和后面吧 ?
I don't know where he's at, but he's missing one heck of a party.
不知他在哪里，他错过了派对
The foosa!
福水 !
The foosa are attacking! Run for your lives!
福水萎草，快逃 !
- Foosa hungry. - Foosa eat.
福水狐了 福水要吃了
l hate spiderwebs.
讨灰奖蛛网
Yeah, thanks a lot, guys.
谢谢你们
Thanks for waiting up. Really appreciate it.
谢洽你们等我，感激不画
Hey, hi. We just got in from New York, and we're looking for a supervisor.
我们刚从弓约来，找话事人
Because we've been sitting on that beach back there for hours,
在沙潍北小时…
and nobody's even bothered to show up.
都盘人求接我们
I don't know how things are normally run around here,
不清楚这和里的日常运作…
but there's been some sort of major screwup, which is cool.
有些混乱，但不要紧
So if you could point us towards the administrative offices, we'll...
请指示行政大楼的位置…
Well, howdy-do.
你好吗 ?
Spider! Spider! Spider on my back!
次蛛 ! 虹蛛 ! 在我背部 !
Maurice, did you see that?
英里斯，看见吗 ?
He scared the foosa away.
他嘛走了福水 !
Come on, Gloria. Get it.
歌莉亚，打死它!
Get it! Get it! Get it!
打死它 ! 打死它 !
- That's it! Smack it! - Get it, get it!
歌莉亚，做得好 !
Whip it! Whip it good! Where'd it go?
重打一顿 ! 它去哪里 ?
King Julien, what are they? What are they?!
朱利安国王，他们是什么 ?
They are aliens. Savage aliens from the savage future.
外星人人，残暴的外星人
They've come to kill us. And take our women. And our precious metals.
他们来条我们 打家动舍，强抢民女
Get up, Mort. Do not be near the king's feet, okay?
毛毛，别靠近国王脚下
We're hiding. Be quiet, everyone. Including me.
躲起来，安静，包括我
Who's making that noise?
谁发出的声音 ?
Oh, it's me again.
噢，又是我
There it is! Get it! Come on, Gloria!
在那里，歌莉亚打死它 !
- Enough! Enough with the stick. - [ think she got it.
角了，打约了 应该给她打死了
Is it still on me? I hate spiders.
还在我身上吗 ? 讨原蛛
It's okay. It's gone.
没事了
They are savages.
他们残暴
Tonight we die.
今晚要打死我们
The feet. I told you... I told you to... I told every...
脚，我已说通
Didn't I tell him about the feet?
所有人不可碰我脚
He did tell you about the feet.
他的确说遇
- Wait. I have a plan. - Really?
我有个主意 真的?
l have devised a cunning test
我有个犹独的办法试探…
to see whether these are savage killers.
他们是否残暴的般手
Hi there.
你好
You let me handle it. Alex handles it. Marty does nothing.
让我来，亚力来，马提别插手
Oh, jeez. Sorry.
噢，对不起
- Oh, Alex, what'd you do? - Stop. Stop. It's okay. It's okay.
亚力，你做什千 ? 别器，别器，没事的
I'm just a silly... Just a silly lion. Oh, jeez!
我只是焦春狮子
- Aw, Alex! - Oh, you poor little baby.
亚力! 小可情
Did that big mean lion scare you?
大狮子嘛款你了 ?
He did? He's a big, bad old puddy tat, isn't he?
他真是焦大款猫味
Come on. Mamai'll hold you. Aww, look at you.
杂妈在，你看你
They are so cute from a reasonable distance.
这距克看的确化可爱
Aren't you the sweetest little thing. I just want to dunk him in my coffee.
真是个可人儿，甜美邦丛
They're just a bunch of pansies.
他们只是一班姆型
I don't know.
不肯定
There's something about that one with the crazy hairdo
全身是所那个…
that I find suspicious.
有可群
Nonsense, Maurice.
杞人胎天
Come on, everybody. Let's go and meet the pansies!
大家一起去见妈型们 !
Presenting your royal highness, our illustrious King Julien XIll,
有请尊贵的国王 朱利安十三世…
self-proclaimed lord of the lemurs, et cetera. Hooray, everybody.
自称为天等鼠王诸如此类
He's got style.
他台型疲好
What is he, like, king of the guinea pigs?
是白老鼠之王 ?
I think it's a squirrel.
似是松鼠
Welcome, giant pansies.
坎迎，妈型巨人
Please feel free to bask in my glow.
请随便被我的光芒能时
- Definitely a squirrel. - Yep. Squirrel.
背定是松鼠 对，松鼠
We thank you with enormous gratitude for chasing away the foosa.
感激你们赶走马岛狸班福水
- The "whossa"? - The foosa.
什么、水″” ? 福水
They annoy us by trespassing, interrupting our parties
狗们擅阅私人地方 打摄我们的派对
- and ripping our limbs off. - Good.
又杀害我们 好呀
We're just trying to find out where the people are, so...
我们只想知人类在哪…
What big teeth you have. Man!
你的牙茧很大
Shame on you, Maurice. Can you not see that you have insulted the freak?
英里斯，么礼 你对这怪胎太不数了
You must tell me, who the heck are you?
告诉我，你们是谁?
I'm Alex. The Alex. And this is Gloria, Marty and Melman.
我是举世扼双的亚力 这是歌莉亚、马提和遵文
And just where are you giants from?
从哪里来的?
We're from New York and...
来自经约…
All hail the New York giants!
经约巨人队万藏!
New York giants!
纽约巨人队!
Is this some sort of inbreeding program?
这可是同化计划的一种?
Il say we just got to ask these bozos where the people are.
我去问这些策蛋人类在哪圭
Excuse me. We bozos have the people, of course.
我们策蛋当然知道
Hey, the bozos have the people.
策蛋知道人类所在
Oh, well, great. Good. Phew.
那好极了
They're up there.
他们在柑上
Don't you love the people? Not a very lively bunch, though.
喜数吗? 可惜洛生气
So do you have any live people?
可有洗的人类 ?
No. Only dead ones.
没有，只有死见
l mean, if we had a lot of live people here,
若有很多活人在…
it wouldn't be called the wild, would it?
这和里就不叫野外，对叶?
The wild?
野外?
Whoa. Hold up there a second, fuzzbucket.
等一阵，毛衣佬
You mean, like,
你是说…
the "live in a mud hut, wipe yourself with a leaf" type wild?
满身泥淖… 用全株屁股那种野外 ?
- Who wipes? - Oy vey.
我们不抹 哇!
- Oy vey! - Oy vey, everybody!
大家一痪哇 !
Could you excuse me for a moment?
怒失陪一障
Get me out of here! We got to get out of here!
救我秦开 ! 我们一定要和逃 !
- Help! - What are you doing?!
你做什么 ?
I'm swimming back to New York.
我要游泳回纽约
I know my chances are slim, but I have to try!
终使机会渺落，也要试 !
- You can't swim! - l said my chances are slim!
你不懂游泳 我知很渺茫 !
Nature! It's all over me! Get it off! can't see! I can't see!
大自然把我包园 ! 走开 ! 我看不见 ! 我看不见 !
Il can see!
看见了1!
Look. There's obviously just been a little mistake.
匠住，只是个小小错误
The people didn't dump us here on purpose.
人类非故意送我们来这壬
As soon as they realize what happened, they'll come looking for us, right?
他们很快便会来找我们
Yeah, right.
对
I don't know the words But we're born free
“我不知歌调，但自由写意^
You know something? I bet they're already on their way.
我肯定他们已在途中
Well, boys, it's going to be ice-cold sushi for breakfast.
将有冰妾的毒司做早餐
Rico.
力高
Well, since I'm doomed to die on this forsaken island,
既然我注定死在这孤岛上…
], Melman Mankiewicz,
我遭文…
being of sound mind and unsound body,
身体衰弱，头脑清醒…
have divided my estate equally among the three of you.
把遗产平分给你们三人
Sorry, Alex.
亚力，你没份了
Hey! A latrine. Nice work, Melman. Outdoor plumbing.
遵文，很美的户外遍所
No, it's not a latrine.
不是户外高所
It's a grave. You sent Melman to his grave. Are you happy?
是填划 你送遵文去死，开心吧 ?
Aw, come on.
列这柑
This isn't the end. This is a whole new beginning.
不是世界末日，是新的开始
This could be the best that's happened.
这或是我们最幸运的一葡
No. No. No. No.
不，不，不，不
No. No. No. No. No. No. This is not the best thing that's happened to us.
不…这不是我们和最幸运的一次
You abused the power of the birthday wish and brought bad luck on all of us.
你的生日顾望为大家带来恶耗
Why'd you tell your wish? You're not supposed to.
为何告诉我们?你不该
I didn't want to tell you. Remember?
我不想说的
- You guys made me tell you. - Oh, okay.
你们要知道 是的
Besides, this isn't bad luck. This is good luck.
涡且这不是恶耗，是好到
Look around. There's no fences, no schedules.
没有轩峙，没有日程表
This place is beautiful. Baby, we were born...
美量的地方，我们生来…
Okay. Okay. I've had enough of this.
我受金了
This is your side of the island, and this is our side of the island.
你留在那站，我们在这站
That is the bad side, where you can prance and skip
那尊是给疯癫的住的…
like a magical pixie horse and do whatever the heck you want.
你可悉随得便
This is the good side for those who love New York and care about going home.
这下是热爱纽约 爱回家的人住的
- Come on. - No, no. Back! Back!
列这柑 退步 ! 退步!
You know what? This isn't good.
这样不太好
Okay! You all have your side, and I'll have mine.
好，慧河汉界
And if you need me, I'll be over here,
若要找我，我就在这…
on the fun side of the island, having a good old time.
好玩、多采多次的一站
This is the fun side,
这下才好玩，我们会…
where we'll have a great time surviving until we go home.
好玩地生存下去直至回家
- A yabbadabbado old time! - This side's the best.
坎乐时光 ! 这边最好玩
That side stinks! You're on the Jersey side of this cesspool!
那站岛类阅气，臭气溃天
- Wilma! - Now what do we do?
现在怎桩 ?
Don't worry. I have a plan to get us rescued.
别担心，我有办法龄并
Can't wait to see the look on Marty's face when he sees this.
马提到时会美效不已
Just look at him. He's helpless without us.
你看他，没我们多广扰助
Shut up, Spalding.
篮球，收天
I've been standing here for hours, man.
我已站了网小时
How long do I have to pose like this?
还要站多久 ?
She is finito.
大功告成
I defy any rescue boat within a million miles
百万哩内经过的船焦…
to miss this baby.
都不会错明她
When the moment is right, we will ignite the beacon of liberty
时机一到，我们就是火…
and be rescued from this awful nightmare!
然后疮并这个恶萝
What do you think? Pretty cool, huh?
你认为呢? 不错吧 ?
- How's the liberty fire going, Melman? - Great. Idiot.
遵文，火准备好未 ? 好极，正章才
I heard that.
我了巩见了
Why can't we just borrow some of Marty's fire?
不如问珊提借火吧 ?
That's wild fire. We're not using wild fire on Lady Liberty.
那是野火，不可用在女神身上
- Now, rub, Melman. - I've been doing...
多续探出火
I can't. l can't. I can't do it. I ju... l can't do it!
不能，不能 我做不来
Fire.
淡
Fire! Fire!
火工火!
Fire!
火 上
Not yet! No, no! No!
还未准备好 !不1不!
Melman, hold still!
递文，列动 !
Jump! Alex, jump!
亚力，跳1!1跳!
Don't worry, cats always land on their...
列担心，猫科动物狗能以…
Face? Man, what kind of cat are you?
面著落 ?你是什么猫科动物?
You maniac!
你这疯子 !
You burned it up!
全烧掉了 !
Darn you!
你去死吧
Darn you all to heck!
全部去死 !
Can we go to the fun side now?
可以去好玩那站吗 ?
Everybody, calm down. Come on. Into your chairs.
大家冷胡，坐好
Let go of his tail.
大家冷静，放并他的尾巴
Separate those two, would you, please?
把他俩分并
You here, you there. Everyone...
你这站，你那站，大家安静
Now, presenting your royal highness, the illustrious blah, blah, blah.
有请尊贵的国王…
You know, et cetera, et cetera. Hooray. Let's go.
你知之后的话啦
Now, everybody,
大家…-
we all have great curiosity about our guests, the New York giants.
都对纽约巨人队充满好奇
- Yes, Willie? - like them.
怎广了? 我喜欢他们
I like them. I liked them first. Before ! even met them I liked them.
我喜霓他们先，未见面已喜坎
I liked them right away. You hate them compared to how much I like them.
我喜欢他们等同你讨原他们
Oh, shut up. You're so annoying!
收声，你真麻烦 !
Now, for as long as we can remember,
由盘古初并…
we have been attacked and eaten by the dreaded foosa.
便唱福水瘟击及角客
The foosa! The foosa are attacking!
福水 ! 福水又来蔓击 !
It's a cookbook! It's a cookbook!
、狐猴美食^
Please. Maurice.
安静，英里其
Quiet!
安静 !
Come on, y‘all. They're not attacking us this very instant.
他们不是现在来散芝
So my genius plan is this:
我的完美计划是 :
We will make the New York giants
与经约巨人队…
our friends and keep them close.
为友
Then, with Mr. Alex protecting us,
宙亚力先生保访我们…
we will be safe and never have to worry
便不再怕….
about the dreaded foosa ever again.
多残的福水了
I thought of that. I thought of that. Yes. Me. I did.
是我想出来的，是我 !
Hold on, everybody. Hold on. I'm just thinking now.
大家等等，我在想
I mean, does anyone wonder why the foosa
可想过和为何福水…
were so scared of Mr. Alex?
怕亚力先生 ?
l mean, maybe we should be scared too.
或许我们也该怕他
What if Mr. Alex is even worse than the foosa?
至力先生比福水更可怕呢 ?
I tell you, that dude just gives me the heebiedabajeebies.
那信伙使我很不安
Maurice, you did not raise your hand.
英里斯，你没举手发言
Therefore, your heinous comment will be stricken from the record.
所以你的评语应被删除
Does anyone else have the heebie-jeebies?
其他人可有意见 ?
No? Good. So shut up.
没有?好 那你收志
When the New York giants wake up,
当纽约巨人队醒来…
we will make sure that they wake up in paradise.
要令他们以为置身天堂
Now, who would like a cookie?
谁要曲奇饼 ?
Yo, Al. Melman and Gloria are over there having a good time.
遵文和歌莉亚玩得很开心
There's room on the fun side for one more.
还可容钢多一人
No, thanks.
不，府谢
Look, I've been thinking. Maybe if you gave this place a chance,
若你肯给这壬一个机会…
I don't know, you might even enjoy yourself.
或许你会自得其和
Marty, I'm tired. I'm hungry.
马提，我又累又狐
I just want to go home.
只想回家
Could you just give it a chance? Think about it.
再想想，给多一炊机会
It really isn't the fun side without you.
那焉没你其实也不好
I know. And then...
我知，之后…
- It's him. - Who is it?
是他 是谁?
It's the pizza man. Who the heck do you think it is?
送薄饼，还会是谁?
Yes? Can I help you?
有何贵干 ?
Can I come to the fun side?
可以来好玩这冰吗?
Beg your pardon?
讲多一次
You know, I've been kind of a jerk.
我是个策蛋
But I've been thinking about what you said, and I'm sorry.
我细想遇你的话，对不起
Welcome to Casa del Wild. Take a load off.
炊迎光枚野外之家，请进
Hey, hey, wipe your feet.
抹乾泽对用
- Alex! - Mi casa is su casa.
亚力! 列客气，当自己家
Very impressive.
环境很好
Hey, have a drink. It's on the house.
先喝杯饮料
This is seawater.
是海水
Oh, you don't swallow it. It's just temporary till the plumbing's done.
别知下，章时性 很快有水喉水
Hey, y'all look hungry.
大家肚钱了
How would you like some of nature's goodness?
不如试试天然食物 ?
You have food?
你有食物 ?
The Fun Side Special, coming up.
好玩特别推介
Seaweed on a stick.
串烧海苔
Seaweed?
海营 ?
On a stick. Don't love it till you try it.
一吃便会爱上
That's unbelievable.
难以置信
- So good. - Well, thanks.
太美味了 谢谢
It does kind of hit the spot, doesn't it?
可以填肚
Well, maybe it could use a little lemon.
加点榨榜会比较好味
No, it's great. It's really great. Doesn't get any better than this.
好极，太好了，扰得顶
Oh, but it does.
好上在后头
Check this out.
你们看
Wow. Would you look at that.
很美呀
It's like billions and billions of helicopters.
像有千历架直界机
It's a shooting star. Make a wish. Quick!
是流星，快许顾 !
Ooh! How about a thick, juicy steak?
厚肉多汁的牛扒
You know what, Alex?
亚力
I promise you I'm going to find you a steak tomorrow if it kills me.
赔了命 我明天也去找顽扒给你
Thanks, Marty.
马提，谢谢
It is getting late. I guess I'm going to...
很晚了，我要…
I think I'm going to hit the sack too.
我也要睡了
Sweet dreams, everyone.
大家发个好欧
Alex.
亚力
What are you doing?
你做什么 ?
Twenty-seven, 28, 29. Thirty black and only 29 white.
27、28、29、30休黑纹 29休和白丝
Looks like you're black with white stripes after all.
你是黑底和白纹
Dilemma solved. Good night.
半题解决，晚安
You see, Maurice, Mr. Alex was grooming his friend.
亚力先生在握摸他的朋友
He is clearly a tender, loving thing.
真是个温系可党的虽西
How can you have the heebie-jeebies for Mr. Alex?
你还怀疑什么 ?
Look at him. He's so cute and plushy.
你看他多可爱系款
I don't think he was grooming him.
他似乎想…
Look more like he was tasting him to me.
吃掉他
Suit yourself, no matter. I don't care.
随便你，我不理
Soon we will put my excellent plan to action.
一切依计行事
All we have to do is wait
我们只需等…
until they are deep in their sleep.
他们入睡为正
How long is this going to take?!
究竟要等多久? !
Well, this sucks!
鬼地方 !
Wake up, Mr. Alex.
起身，亚力先生
Rise and shining.
晨早起床，清新闻六
Wakey-waking, Mr. Alex!
起身啦，亚力先生 !
Wake up! Alex!
起身 ! 亚力先生 !
You suck your thumb?
你受拇指?
Where are we? What the heck is going on?
我们在哪里 ? 发生什么事 ?
Where's the beach? Take it easy.
沙溢呢? 别紧张
- Who built a forest? - Don't be alarmed, giant freaks.
谁建了森林 ? 别紧张，怪物巨人
While you were asleep,
当你们睡著时
we simply took you to our little corner of heaven.
我们把你们哲来天堂的一角
Welcome to Madagascar.
炊迎来到马达加斯加
- Mada-who-ah? - What?
马达什么加 ? 什么 ?
No, not whooha. Ascar.
是马达加斯加
Marty. It's...
马提，这…,
Just like my mural back at the zoo.
囚动物回炉上的书一样
Oh, no, fella, that is the real deal right there.
这幅是真的
Look at that, that's not a bad view.
看，风最不错
That's the thing that you were always looking at, but it's actually there.
你萝赛以求的就在眼前
- That's the real version of... - How about once around the park?
这是真实版 不如跑一圈 ?
Let's get our blood pumping, lungs breathing this fresh air.
让血液澎涛 避情呼吸新鲜空气
Who's with me?!
谁跟我来?
Naw. I don't think I could... You're it!
我不行 追我 !
Hey! Want to play around?
再跑多园
Got you there!
追到你啦 !
Come here!
返来呀!
You're it.
被追到了
Hey, stop that! Hey, you're crazy!
停止 ! 你傻了!
Okay, Marty, I'm it.
马提，玩金了
I'm it. I'm it. You win.
我输了，你赢了
Come on, Alex, get in the groove.
亚力，别抬愤
l haven't eaten in two days.
我十日没吃遇
My blood sugar's real low. I just don't have the energy.
我血糖很低，没精力
I don't think that's your problem.
不是这个问题
First of all, that's not how you run in the wild.
在野外不是这样跑的
Let's go. Put the rubber to the road!
避情去跑
You just have to let out that inner lion.
释放真正的你
- Now, who's the cat? - Marty, I really don't...
谁是森林之王? 马提，我真的…
You are, that's who. Come on! Here we go!
是你，来，一起跑
That's it. Let's build up some steam! You the cat.
就是这样，渐渐加速
- Who's the cat? - You the cat.
谁是森林之王? 是你
Who's the cat? Who's the cat?
谁是森林之王?…
I'm the cat!
就是我 !
Surprise!
奖喜 !
You're it. You're it!
你坦了 ! 你输了 !
Can't juke the cat. Cat's too quick.
森林之王所向乱散
l feel like a mile-high pastrami on rye on the fly from the deli in the sky!
我像要一郝溃天去
- Let's go wild! - Now you're talking!
我们去狂野一亚 ! 这才像话
Man! I feel different.
我如脱胎换骨
Kind of charged up or something.
像从新充满力量
- Like you said, baby, it's... - Crackalacking.
正如你所说… 擂得顶
- Ain't that right, Melman? - Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
对吗，六文 ? 对，对
I'm in heaven.
我置身天堂
You see, Maurice, Alex is now our friend and the foosas are nowhere to be seen.
亚力现是我们的朋友 福水们都经踊了
It could be said that my plan is working
我的计划汪效了…
in a very good working kind of way.
非常成功
Alex. You got to try some of this.
亚力，要试试这个
I feel good. Feel like a king again.
感觉很好，又再成王了
King?
王?
You should see his act.
你该看他表演
Come on, Alex, why don't you show him some of your act.
亚力，露两手给他看看
Oh. No, I really don't think I could... Okay.
不，我不行…好吧
Ladies and gentlemen. Primates of all ages.
先生女士们
The wild proudly presents:
野外诚意呈献 :
The king.
森林之王
Alex the lion!
狮子亚力 !
E flat, fellas.
E低调
Yeah! The king is in the house!
森林之王宴到 !
See, if he is the king, then where is his crown? I've got a crown.
他的皇冠吕? 我全有皇冠
Got a very nice one. And it's here on my head.
非常漂亮，在我头上
Look at it. Have I got it on?
我可有戴著?
Do the roar, man. Do the roar.
吼叫给大家看
Wow. I've never heard that one before.
从未贩过这样吼叫
Yeah! Go wild, man! Come on!
台情狂野
Break out the wave!
大家做人浪
Excuse me.
不好意思
You're biting my butt.
你咬著我的屁股
- No, I'm not. - Yes, you are.
没有 有
- What did you do? - You just bit me!
你做什么 ? 你咳我
No. I didn't. Did I?
我没有，有了吗 ?
You kind of did.
好似有
What the heck is wrong with you?
你究竟怎效了 ?
Why'd you bite me?
为什么咬我?
- Man, it's because you are his dinner. - What?!
因为你是他的晚餐 什么 ?
- Excuse me? - That's dumb.
说什么 ? 列俐了
Come, come, Maurice. What is a simple bite on the buttocks among friends?
朋友之间咬一口有什么天你 ?
Here, give me a nibble.
来，咬我屁股
The party is over, Julien. Your brilliant plan has failed.
你的计划失败 了
What are you talking about?
你在说什么 ?
Your friend here is what we call
你朋友是件…
a deluxe-model hunting and eating machine.
各革版猎角机器
And he eats steak...
他吃牛失…
. which is you.
就是你
- Get out of here. - Okey-dokey, Maurice, I admit it.
别说笑了 英里斯，我承认
The plan failed.
计划失败
All is lost! We're all doomed.
我们全部要死
The foosas will come back and gobble us with their mouths because...
福水们会回来吞噬我们…
...we are all steak.
因为我们全是牛扒
I'm steak! Me, me, me!
我是牛扒 1我1我!
Mr. Alex cannot stay here.
至力先生不能留下
He belongs with his own kind on the foosa side of the island.
他属恭福水那下
By the power vested in me,
根据森林的法例
by the law of the jungle, blah, blah, blah, blah...
诸如此类…
Be gone!
准开 !
What? Come on, do! look like a steak to you?
我似件牛拉吗?
Yeah!
似
- He's going savage. - Run for your lives.
他要软性大发了 大家快逃
Marty, run!
马提，逃 !
A bull's eye. Excellent shot, Maurice.
英里斯，好眼界
Thank you.
谢谢
Marty?
马提?
I'm so sorry, Marty.
对不起，台提
What is wrong with me?
我究竟怎入了?
What have I done?
我做了什么 ?
It's true. I'm a monster.
是真的，我是禽软
I got to get out of here.
我要内并这壬
What have I done? This is a nightmare.
我做了什么 ? 简直显萝
And it's all my fault.
失去了垩力
Now, because of me, we've lost Alex.
全是我的错
Well, what are we going to do?
那我们该怎广办 ?
Weill find a way to help him. That's what we'll do.
我们要他
Come on, we are New Yorkers, right?
我们是弓约客
We're tough. We're gritty.
我们强悍，我们有胆量
We're adaptable!
通应力强
And we are not going to lay down like a bunch of Melmans.
不会像遭文般脆弱
No, we're not.
绝对不会
Oh. Gloria.
歌莉亚
That was not me, okay? That was the boat.
不是我发出的，是那艘般
- The boat! - The boat?
船! 船?
The boat's come back for us! Come on, guys, we got to flag it down.
回来找我们，向它求救
There it is!
它来了 !
- Hey, over here! - Over here!
这站 !
Melman, give me a lift. Hurry up! Lift me up!
遵文，举起我，快是 !
Help! Help! Help!
救命! 救命1救命!
- Oh, my neck. My neck. You guys. - Over here!
我的疆 这站 !
- Melman! Steady. This way! - You have no idea how much this hurts.
递文，站稳 你根本不知有多痛
Hey, boat! We're over here!
船家 ! 我们在这站 !
Look! It's turning! It's coming back! It's coming back!
看，它掉头了，掉头了 !
Come on! Come on, baby!
裤贝，这焉 !
Yes! You guys.
大家看
You flag down that boat. I'll get Alex.
你招呼艘船，我去找亚力
Whoa! Hold on there.
等等!
You cannot go back there by yourself.
你不能独自去
Aw, come on. I know Alex.
亚力知可以内开
He hears we're rescued, he'll snap right out of it.
一定会出来
The people are coming. They can help us.
人类来了，来救我们
Melman's right. The people will Know what to do.
对，人类会懂得怎做
Now, we got to flag down that boat.
快叫焦船过来
Now, this is more like it.
这里比较像样
You?! Oh, ma... Where are the people?
你?人类呢?
We killed them and ate their livers.
杀了他们，吃掉他们的肝
Got you, didn't I?
说笑而已
Just kidding, doll, the people are fine.
那些人类没事
They're on a slow lifeboat to China.
他们的救生艇很落后
Hey, I Know you two.
嘿，我认得你俩
Where's that psychotic lion and our monochromatic friend?
神经贸狮耶和黑和白朋友呢 ?
Marty? He's righ... Where did he go? He was right behind us.
马提，他去了哪里?刚才还在
He went back for Alex. He's going to get himself killed!
他去找亚力，会被吃掉
Well, boys, our monochromatic friend's in danger.
我们的黑白朋友有危险
Looks like we have a job to do.
看来要设法摊救
Captain's log: Embarking into hostile environment.
船长记事簿 : 进入作有战状态
Kowalski. We'll need to win the hearts and the minds of the natives.
高芋斯基，要安括原居民
Rico. We'll need special tactical equipment.
力高，准人备战略装备
We're going to face extreme peril.
将要面对强顽困难
Private probably won't survive.
卒仔，你或许要粕粕
Alex! Come out, Alex!
亚力，出来呀 ! 亚力 !
The boat's here! We can go home!
船来了，我们可以回家
Alex! Alex! Alex! Alex! Alex!
亚力 1 垩力!
Alex!
亚力!
Marty?
马提?
Snap out of it, Alex. The boat came back. We can get out of here.
出来 ! 船来了，我们可以郊开
We can go back to civilization, and everything will be like it used to be.
回到文明世界，一切如常
Stay back.
退和后
Please.
请
Alex, you're no monster. You're my friend.
亚力，你不是禽软，是我朋友
We're a team. You and me, remember?
我俩是葛幻组合，你和我
I don't want to hurt you.
我不想伤害你
Alex.
亚力
l ain't leaving without you.
你不走，我不苑开
Alex? I'm thinking of a song.
亚力，我想起一首歌
It's a wonderful song. I'm sure you're familiar with it.
动节的歌，你一定会唱
Start spreadin' the news
开始散人饰消息…
I'm leaving today
我今天要离开
We are a great big part of it
我们是当中一大部份
Come on, you know the words. Two little words.
你记得歌词，雨个字
Please don't make me sing this by myself.
别要我一个人唱
You really don't want to hear me sing this by myself.
你不会想职我独自唱的
Uh, Alex? Could you come out here for a minute?
型力，可出来一会吗?
Hey, Alex, a little help.
亚力，旭梨忙
Help me!
救命呀 !
Alex! Help!
亚力!
Help me! Anybody, help me! Somebody!
救命呀 ! 来人呀!
Help!
救命呀 !
- Melman? - That's right, baby.
遵文 ? 这就对了
Run!
逃 !
- What's the plan? - This is the plan.
有何和后著 ? 这就是后著
- Foosa hungry. - Foosa eat.
福水肚饶 福水要吃
This is the plan?
这就是后著 ?
Foosa halt.
福水停手 !
Come and get it.
死未
There's too many of them, skipper.
队长，太多了
It's been a real pleasure serving with you boys.
很荣幸和你们共事
Alex?
亚力?
That's my kill.
那是我的猎物
Mine.
我的
Alex hungry.
亚力肛猎
Alex eat.
亚力要吃
It's showtime.
表演了时间
Thanks for not giving up on me.
马提，洽诗你没放豪我
Man, you almost gave me a heart attack. You can't just come sneak up on me.
你差点把我嘛死，别这广施秘
Just because you're a lion... Let go of me. Let go of me.
你是狂子，放并我，放并我
We're getting out of here. Guys, just go with me on this.
谁并人这里，跟著我做
Like I said, it's showtime.
表演了时间
Mine.
是我的
My kill.
我的猎物
They're all mine.
全部是我的
It's the king of the beasts! Oh, no!
万软之王!
- Don't eat me! - He's big and scary!
狮子先生，别吃我 他可怕
Fear me! Savagery beyond comprehension.
我乱恶不作、残酷匈猛
- lam far too young to die! - You're a monster! A monster, I say!
英年旱逝 ! 你是禽软 !
- And, you! - Me?
你 ! 我?
Oh, you want some of this? Ooh! You better run for your lives.
要试吗?
- Somebody call a cop! - He's psychotic!
通知警察 ! 他瘦了!
This is my territory. Understand?
这是我的领土，明和白叶?
I never, ever want to see you on my turf again.
我不想再见到你们
Yeah! You the cat!
你是森林之王
Got my boy back!
你返来啦 !
I did it!
我成功了 !
Give me some love! The plan worked! The plan worked! I'm very clever!
计划成功 ! 计划成功 ! 我很鸡明
I'm the one, baby! Come on. Time to robot.
我最了不起! 赦来跳霹压舞
lam very clever king.
我是个隐明的皇常
lam super genius.
我是个天才
lam robot king of the monkey things.
是马柳族之王
- Compute, compute. - So, what's for lunch?
开动，开动 午餐是什么 ?
- Close those eyes. - Why do I have to?
并上眼睛 和为什么要… ?
- Do it. - They're closed.
照做 闭上了
- Tighter. - Yes, sir.
于紧些 是的
- No peeking. - They're closed.
不准偷看 于紧了
Rico.
力高
Open that hatch.
张开口
Fire in the hole. Now chew.
发射
Chew like you mean it. Savor it.
现在咀鄙 细心 咀中 晓 嗜 味道
- And? - Well?
如何? 怎样 ?
Pretty good, right?
不错吧 ?
There's always Plan B.
名有和后著的
This is better than steak.
比牛拉美味
love it. I love it!
我喜霓 ! 很喜雪 !
The kitty loves the fishy.
猎是喜坎吃和急的
Well, I propose a toast.
我来祝酒
Now, he may be a pain in the butt at times...
他有时真的很届人…
And trust me, I know.
但相信我
But this cat proved to me without a doubt
这焦大和猎…
that his heart is bigger than his stomach.
心地善良
- To Alex.
阁亚力 !
Enough! Stop it!
狗了，别再旺 !
What do you think? Should we head back to New York?
怎样 ? 要回弓约叶?
I don't know. I mean, this is your dream.
是你的欧理
You sure you want to leave?
拾得礁开吗 ?
I don't care where we are.
不理身在何不
As long as we're together, it doesn't matter to me.
最重要我们在一起
Well, in that case...
那样的话，…
Yo. Rico. I'll take 300 orders to go.
力高，要300份…
Hai.
外误
But before you leave, l have an announcement to make.
走之前，我有事宣人饰
So shut up, everyone, please. Thank you.
大家安静，谢谢
After much deep and profound brain things inside my head,
经过详加考虑…
l have decided to thank you
感潮你…
for bringing peace to our home.
带给我们平安
And to make you feel good,
我有份纪念品…
I'm going to give you this lovely parting gift.
送给你
No, I couldn't. Really, I can't take your crown.
我不能收你的皇冠
That's okay, I've got a bigger crown.
没所谓，我有个大的
It's got a gecko on it.
随冠送上壁虎
Look at him shake. Go, Stevie, go!
看物净所
- Bye, little fuzzbuckets! - Thanks for everything!
再见，毛示人戏 ! 多府大家 !
- So long! - Bye-bye, now.
保重 再见
- Arrivederci. - Bye-bye.
和后会扰期
- Toodle-oo! - See you later, crocodile.
珍重 甸鱼，膛些见
Maurice, my arm is tired. Wave it for me.
英里斯，我累了，替我挥手
Faster, you naughty little monkey.
快点，你这小I皮
By the time we get back to New York, it'll be the middle of winter.
回到纽约时该是深冬
So I was just thinking, why rush?
不用和急著回去
Maybe we could make a few side stops along the way.
不妨沿途四周园看看
- Maybe Paris. - You just read my mind.
不如巴黎 所见略同
- l was thinking Spain. - Run with the bulls.
我想去西班牙 问牛节
- What about Fiji? - Canada. Can we?
菲济呢 ? 不如去加拿大 ?
Cheap meds.
平价医疗保健
wouldn't even mind coming back here sometime.
间中回来下也不妨
- l could do that. - You could say that again.
好呀 移成
- Skipper? - lalways wanted to go to Australia.
队长? 我一直想去澳洲
Don't you think we should tell them that the boat's out of gas?
可要告诉他们船快矢油 ?
Just smile and wave, boys. Smile and wave.
只管笑和挥手、笑和挥手